早安,我們今天討論「真正的祝福」
「真正的祝福」
你們希望得到甚麼祝福
一開始時,你們會…
你們會在群組中準備一些祝福
好嗎?我會考驗你們
有甚麼祝福…
馬上有福氣
馬上有福氣,好,非常好
你會跟外婆說甚麼
「新年快樂」,然後呢
「身體健康」
好,你準備一些祝福,然後我考驗你
好,請開始
好,大家準備好了嗎
誰準備好了
我想到馬可福音
馬年可以傳福音,馬可福音
非常好,下一個
馬上有星星
星星?星星即是…
「入學順利」
好… 心想事成
好,長大了
馬上順暢,馬上幸福
非常好,好
我們說跟長輩說祝福語
最好是知道他們的鄉下
有潮州鄉下嗎?知道嗎
有,你會怎樣就怎樣說,要說嗎
不是,說潮州話的「身體健康」
剛才我教了我後面那個
叫做「身體健康」
記住,他說「馬上有錢」
好,我們中國人很想有福
我們都想有祝福,對吧
我們想要甚麼?有身體健康
有錢,對吧
好學位,想有好學位的祝福
有多朋友,有好的父母,好的家庭
但我們中國的文化是很害怕的
我們害怕甚麼…
下一頁,我們害怕甚麼…
冷死了,有甚麼?嚇死了
還有甚麼?我們中國人害怕甚麼
害怕甚麼
害怕死了,對吧
我們的單位有四樓嗎
有人想住四樓嗎
14樓呢?一定死
14樓,對吧
我們中國人非常害怕
我們還害怕甚麼?害怕甚麼
害怕甚麼?有甚麼?沒甚麼害怕
好,有人知道我們新年有一個故事
我們有一個故事
「中國新年故事」,你知道是甚麼意思嗎
你知道「中國新年故事」是甚麼意思嗎
好,我們請我們的演員上來
我們現在請我們的演員上來
掌聲鼓勵
很久以前,有一種名為「年」的怪獸
每年除夕,就會從山上下來
傷人,毀壞村落,吃光山畜
每逢年尾,村民都很害怕
家家戶戶都準備上山躲避
老婆婆,我可以要點乾糧和水嗎
我很肚餓和渴
你做甚麼?天快黑了,為何不上山
年壽快來了,你跟我上去躲避吧
我不用怕,我有上帝的同在
你知道年壽有多恐怖嗎
我有上帝的同在,上帝比一切大
我不怕,不過我可以借用你的房子嗎
那你住吧,我上山了 好
到了半夜,年壽好像預言般現身
他看見村裡一片漆黑
只有老婆婆的家燈火通明
就大喊一聲,衝了過去
我奉上帝的名,趕你這個年壽走
年壽聽到上帝的名,嚇得魂飛魄散
就魂飛魄散,落荒而逃
為何我的房子完全沒事?很神奇
因為我有上帝的同在
你看到嗎?二馬內利主必同在
從此之後,村民每年除夕
都過得很平安、很快樂
年壽再沒有出現
好,給他們一點掌聲
這是中國新年的故事
每年都有怪獸叫年
每年都會下來吃人
所以中國的文化充滿恐懼
但我們基督教的信仰不是說恐懼
而是說有信仰,是恐懼對信仰
中國人很怕死、怕冷、怕嚇死
怕年壽下來
但主耶穌跟我們說甚麼
我們要有信心
我們今天會看耶穌說甚麼
我們看祂的慈悲
我們會讀5章,讀在一起
好,讀在一起,1、2、3
當耶穌看到群眾
祂上到山頂坐下
祂的徒弟們來教導祂們
然後祂說
「祝福貧民和靈魂
因為他們是天堂的王國
祝福貧民
因為他們會繼承地球
祝福善良和善良
因為他們會看到神
祝福被迫害的人
因為他們是正義的
因為他們是天堂的王國
當人們侮辱你、迫害你
或者因為我而對你
說出各種邪惡的說話
請憐憫而高興
因為天堂是你的獎勵
因為同樣地
他們也迫害了在你面前的聖徒」
好,我們讀在一起
「神父,我們來到你面前
我們想慶祝新年
我們也想學習你的祝福
請教導我們透過你的靈魂
我們在祂的名下祈禱」
今天我們會學四件事
第一是「信仰國王」
「信仰祂的王國」
「信仰祂的寬恕」
「信仰永遠」
第一,我們會看「祝福貧民」
「祝福貧民
因為他們會繼承地球」
我們左邊,這是甚麼
這是甚麼?竹,是嗎?
竹,是嗎?竹
竹,竹是用來做甚麼的
給熊貓吃
給熊貓吃,對了
竹的特徵是甚麼
它們很柔軟、很強壯
很甚麼?是很甚麼
在樹上來說,它們是最強壯的嗎
它們不是最強壯的
它們是最弱的嗎?它不是最弱的
這些竹有甚麼強度特徵
有甚麼?它們有甚麼
它們可以旋轉
這就是為何我們在建築上使用竹
它們很容易建造、結合
而且它們在大風的時候
它們可以旋轉、移動
它們很像穩固的東西,是嗎
弱勢是甚麼?弱勢是甚麼
弱勢不是弱勢
弱勢在控制之下
所以為何說「Blessed are the meek」
「Blessed are the meek」,為甚麼
因為它們懂得如何控制自己
它們可以投靠力量
但卻不會被毀壞
中國人拜年時會怎樣
叫甚麼?鞠躬,是嗎
恭喜,是嗎
好,下一頁
我們這樣做,叫甚麼
恭喜,為何我們會恭喜
為何中國人會恭喜
你們今天見婆婆、媽媽會恭喜嗎
恭喜,為何中國人會恭喜
為甚麼?有人知道嗎
這是代表尊敬、榮耀,是嗎
我們向婆婆、媽媽、公公
祝你們身體健康、新年快樂,是嗎
為甚麼?因為這是一種榮耀、尊敬
我們要尊敬我們的長輩
為何耶穌說
「Blessed are the meek」
「for they will inherit the earth」
「It's because those who respect authority」
「they will be blessed」
誰建立了地球上的權力
誰建立了你的主導人
誰建立了你的長輩
誰建立了香港的管治系統
誰建立了,甚至允許中國擁有總統
誰?究竟是誰
就是主人
主人建立了國王和權力
所以最終,我們要向主人報仇
我們要向主人報仇
因為每個老師、主席、教師、國務卿
每個人有一天會負責任
最終他們會負責任於誰
他們會負責任於主人
所以我們都要向主人報仇
所以第一個教訓是「信仰國王」
正如中國文化
我們要尊重我們的長輩、父母
我們要信仰國王、尊重國王
他就是最強的人
他就是宇宙上的權力
第二個教訓是
Blessed are the poor in spirit
我們今天很希望有甚麼
這個新年是利是
利是是我們期望的
我們期望的是富貴和錢
是嗎?
但耶穌這樣說
Blessed are the poor in spirit
為甚麼?
Poor in spirit
Why are they blessed? 為甚麼這些人有福?
這些人不是很慘嗎?
Why are the poor in spirit blessed?
有人知道嗎?
我們中國文化很喜歡甚麼?
下一頁
很喜歡甚麼?
給面子,是嗎?
Save face,是嗎?
給面子
我們怎樣給面子?
我們怎樣save face?
How do we save face?
我們怎樣給面子?
Auntie Winnie,我們怎樣給面子?
在我們的中國文化
稱讚別人?
OK
好的,不好的事情就不說
是嗎?哪個家庭是這樣的?
Whose family is like that?
No?
只是說好的事情
不,是Stanley的叔叔
Stanley叔叔和Fiona叔叔
只是說好的事情
怎樣給面子?
有人給面子嗎?
Save face
有人嗎?No?
Snatch for the bill
哪個家庭很搶費用?
OK…
We like to save face,是嗎?
有些事情不想說
不好的事情我們不會說
有些事情是負面的
我們不會說
We like to save face
Jesus says, "Blessed are the poor in spirit"
我們中國人只展示我們好的一面
We only show the good side
不展示我們不好的一面
我們不展示我們的弱點
我們不會哭
我們是很大男人的
We don't show weakness
But Jesus is saying here
Blessed are the poor in spirit
What does it mean?
是否你很窮
然後才可以有神的blessing?
是不是這樣?
No, it means
those who are poor in spirit
meaning they are longing
they are longing for the Lord
they are poor spiritually
so they desire the Lord more
明白嗎?
Do you understand?
So the next faith is faith in His kingdom
Blessed are those who are poor spiritually
that they will seek the Lord
and that is what the blessing is
That those who have faith in His kingdom
they will be blessed
OK, the next blessing is
Blessed are the pure in heart
for they will see God
我們新年的時候會怎樣?
Right side,我們會怎樣?
我們家樂會怎樣?
We need to clean our house
有沒有人新年會整理家居?
OK,兩個,三個
OK,為甚麼我們會整理家居?
中國人
今天是年廿八,所以要洗垃圾
OK,你解釋一下
你的理論是甚麼?
洗垃圾就是令大家乾淨
乾淨就自然有福
OK, all right
Blessing is connected with being clean
你乾淨就會有Blessing
But Jesus is saying
Not only is our house need to be clean
But our hearts need to be clean
And so上個星期我們學了甚麼?
上個星期我們學了誰被醫治?
誰被醫治?
一個paralyzed person
他四個朋友帶他去見耶穌
然後耶穌就叫他起立
Pick up your mat and walk
So the most important thing
is not just that our house is clean
But our hearts need to be clean as well
We need to seek the forgiveness of Jesus
Faith in His forgiveness
OK, the fourth blessing is
Blessed are those who are persecuted
Blessed are those who insult you, persecute you
Or falsely say bad things because of me
For yours is the kingdom
我們右邊吃甚麼?
我們新年的時候吃年糕
好吃嗎?喜歡吃嗎?
喜歡吃,OK
我們這個sweetness
The sweetness of年糕會多久?
How long will it last?
It will be temporary
The sweetness of年糕 is temporary
However, Jesus is saying
Those who persecute you, right?
These things, they are also temporary
They are also temporary
However, what is eternal?
His kingdom is eternal
他們神之前說
Blessed are you
Rejoice and be glad
Because great is your reward in heaven
Great is your reward in heaven
The next slide says
Rejoice and be glad
Because great is your reward in heaven
中國人是很寄望
有年糕,有食物,是嗎?
但是食物是temporary
These things are temporary
And what Jesus is asking us to look for
Is not just temporary things
But eternal things
And the only thing that lasts forever
What are the only things that last forever?
It is heaven
It is our relationship with the Lord
It is us bringing people to the Lord
我們帶人去認識主耶穌
他們也會上天堂
所以這些東西是會last forever
These are the only things that last forever
我們中國人是很seek temporary blessing
But God is telling us
Jesus is telling us
to seek eternal blessing
eternal blessing
The next slide is this
What does this mean?
What is this saying?
你猜一下
Faith over fear
We need to have faith
More faith in Jesus
And our faith in Jesus
has to be greater than our fear of death
and our fear of death
So four things today
第一
我們要有faith in the King
He is the one and only one
that is worthy of our respect
our worship
We need to have faith in His kingdom
that we belong in His kingdom
我們不是每個東西都要perfect
everything is great
No
God is wanting us to go to Him
just as we are
We are sinners
We are weak
We need Him
God is accepting us into His kingdom
And next thing is faith in His forgiveness
神是要恕我們的
He forgives us of our sin
And lastly, faith in eternity
這個字是福
What does it mean?
Blessing means God
plus one, plus mouth, plus field
What is it?
有沒有人看過?
這個福這個字
這個福是remind you of what?
什麼story?
這個什麼story?
What story is it?
Creation, right?
God spoke
And then the world began
And all the world was created
And the Garden of Eden
was created
So true blessing
comes with that relationship
with the Lord
當下和神的關係之前是怎樣的?
之前是怎樣的?
They had peace
They had blessing
是不是?
沒有罪的
但是為什麼有罪?
因為他們choose to go against God
They ate the fruit of the knowledge
of the good and evil
所以這個世界就充滿什麼?
充滿罪
That's why we have original sin
That's why we choose, right?
Selfishness over righteousness
所以神怎樣去解決這個問題?
How did God solve this problem?
God solved this problem by sending Jesus
這個word 福
你調轉了是怎樣的?
福來到
How does blessing come?
It is through the cross
Faith in Jesus Christ
Jesus Christ brought the true blessing
Okay, Jesus Christ brought the true blessing
我們看下一條片子
下一條片子是怎樣的?
我們有沒有人在你家裡擺這些叫什麼?
有沒有人會寫揮春的?
這個是Gabriel寫的
漂亮嗎?
我們一起讀一次
1,2,3
以馬來尼主必同在
Okay, all right
你記不記得Passover story
Passover story是什麼天使?
有十字架
There are ten plagues, right?
What are the ten plagues?
Name out
Frogs
還有呢?
What are the ten plagues?
Yes, river into blood
還有呢?
Ten plagues
是什麼?
有些東西下來的
Yes, the angel of death
Yes, 還有呢?
Locusts
Darkness
Hail
There's like
What's it called?
Grasshoppers
Oh yeah, that's locusts
There's all these things
最後一個是the angel of death
The angel of death會怎樣?
他們會怎樣?
They will kill all the first born
誰是first born?
Who is first born here?
You guys will all be
You will all meet the angel of death
Okay?
神就和以色列人說了什麼?
你要怎樣?
You slaughter a lamb
And then
用他的血怎樣?
You paint your door with blood
Okay?
然後那個angel of death會怎樣?
Will pass over
這個story is foreshadowing what?
What is this story foreshadowing?
That one day Jesus will come
And he will protect us
Because he is the lamb that is slaughtered
His blood was shed
His blood was painted on the door
So that the angel of death would pass over
And that we would receive true blessing
We would receive true blessing
So this day I hope
That we are not receiving just temporary blessings
That we are seeking for true blessing
And true blessing comes from the Lord
True blessing comes to those who are poor in spirit
That they seek after the Lord
True blessing comes from those
Who are persecuted because of Jesus
For they will be
They will receive the reward in heaven
True blessing comes to those who are pure in heart
Because not only are we pure on the outside
We are pure on the inside
When we receive the forgiveness of the Lord
And blessed are those who are meek
Who respect and give glory to the Lord
So this day I hope you have true blessing
And this blessing comes from the blesser
Not from anything else
Okay, so let's pray as the band comes up
I just want to give a moment here today
Today we learned about blessing
Who truly wants to be blessed today
Maybe you've come to church for the hundredth time
And you heard about Jesus
Maybe this is your first time
And you've been coming to church since you were a kid
But you don't really know Jesus
You truly have not gotten to know Jesus personally
Maybe you've been seeking the Lord all your life
You've been seeking the Lord all your life
Maybe you've been seeking blessings all your life
From things outside
From things of the world
But today God is asking you
Seek me, I am the true blessing
It's not the red pockets
It's not the good food
The best thing I can give you
Is true peace with our Creator
That is only through Jesus Christ
Is there anybody here today
That wants to receive the true blessing of Jesus Christ
That is true peace
And a restored relationship with Him
Forgiveness, eternity
And the fruits that come with following Him
Is there anybody here today
That wants to receive the true blessing of Jesus
Please raise your hand
And we will pray a prayer
To receive the blessing of Jesus Christ
Is there anybody else
That wants to receive the true blessing
All right, let's pray together
Pray with me
Dear Heavenly Father
Pray with me out loud
One, two, three
Dear Heavenly Father
We thank you that you sent Jesus
That He is the true blessing
All the things on earth are temporary
But when Jesus died on the cross
For my sins
He gave me eternal blessing
I now receive you, Jesus
To be my Lord and Savior
To be my true blessing
May you make me the man and woman
That you want me to be
To be a blessing to others
In Jesus' name I pray, amen